[
    {
        "question": "Two projectiles A and B are thrown at 40 m/s and 60 m/s at angles 30\u00b0 and 60\u00b0. The ratio of their ranges is:",
        "options": [
            "4 : 9",
            "2 : 3",
            "1 : 1",
            "3 : 2"
        ],
        "correctOption": "4 : 9",
        "id": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "A particle of mass 500 g has velocity (2t i + 3t\u00b2 j) m/s. Force at t=1s is (i + xj). Find x:",
        "options": [
            "4",
            "3",
            "6",
            "2"
        ],
        "correctOption": "3",
        "id": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Two forces A and A/2 are perpendicular. Resultant magnitude is:",
        "options": [
            "(\u221a5)A/2",
            "5A/2",
            "(\u221a5)A\u00b2/2",
            "(\u221a5)A/4"
        ],
        "correctOption": "(\u221a5)A/2",
        "id": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Four particles A, B, C, D have same momentum. Which has max kinetic energy?",
        "options": [
            "D",
            "C",
            "A",
            "B"
        ],
        "correctOption": "A",
        "id": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "A ball is thrown up at 150 m/s. Ratio of velocity after 3s and 5s is (x+1)/x. Find x:",
        "options": [
            "6",
            "10",
            "\u20135",
            "5"
        ],
        "correctOption": "5",
        "id": 5
    },
    {
        "question": "Weight of a body on Earth is 400 N. At half Earth's radius depth, it will be:",
        "options": [
            "200 N",
            "300 N",
            "100 N",
            "Zero"
        ],
        "correctOption": "200 N",
        "id": 6
    },
    {
        "question": "Moment of inertia of a semicircular ring about axis through center perpendicular to plane is xMR\u00b2. Find x:",
        "options": [
            "4",
            "1",
            "6",
            "2"
        ],
        "correctOption": "1",
        "id": 7
    },
    {
        "question": "Aluminium rod with Y = 7.0\u00d710\u00b9\u2070 N/m\u00b2 undergoes strain 0.04%. Energy per unit volume is:",
        "options": [
            "5600",
            "8400",
            "2800",
            "11200"
        ],
        "correctOption": "5600",
        "id": 8
    },
    {
        "question": "If wire length doubled and cross-section halved, Young's modulus becomes:",
        "options": [
            "Y/4",
            "4Y",
            "Y",
            "2Y"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Y",
        "id": 9
    },
    {
        "question": "Two satellites A and B in same orbit. A is twice mass of B. Which is same for both?",
        "options": [
            "Potential energy",
            "Total energy",
            "Kinetic energy",
            "Speed"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Speed",
        "id": 10
    },
    {
        "question": "A body cools from 80\u00b0C to 60\u00b0C in 5 min. Room temp is 20\u00b0C. Time to cool from 60\u00b0C to 40\u00b0C:",
        "options": [
            "500 s",
            "25 / 3 s",
            "450 s",
            "420 s"
        ],
        "correctOption": "500 s",
        "id": 11
    },
    {
        "question": "Average KE of a monatomic molecule is 0.414 eV. Temp is:",
        "options": [
            "3000 K",
            "3200 K",
            "1600 K",
            "1500 K"
        ],
        "correctOption": "3200 K",
        "id": 12
    },
    {
        "question": "Temp of gas is -78\u00b0C and avg KE is k. Temp for avg KE = 2k is:",
        "options": [
            "117",
            "320",
            "160",
            "-157"
        ],
        "correctOption": "117",
        "id": 13
    },
    {
        "question": "Engine between boiling and freezing points of water. Efficiency:",
        "options": [
            "2, 3 and 4 only",
            "2 and 3 only",
            "2 and 4 only",
            "1 and 2 only"
        ],
        "correctOption": "2 and 4 only",
        "id": 14
    },
    {
        "question": "Statement I: Adding heat raises temp. Statement II: Positive work done increases volume.",
        "options": [
            "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
            "Both Statements are true",
            "Both Statements are false",
            "Statement I is false but Statement II is true"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
        "id": 15
    },
    {
        "question": "Fundamental frequency of a closed pipe = first overtone of open pipe. If open pipe is 60 cm, closed pipe is:",
        "options": [
            "15",
            "20",
            "25",
            "60"
        ],
        "correctOption": "15",
        "id": 16
    },
    {
        "question": "For y = sin(\u03c9t) + cos(\u03c9t), the amplitude is:",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "1.414",
            "2",
            "1.5"
        ],
        "correctOption": "1.414",
        "id": 17
    },
    {
        "question": "In SHM, when displacement is 1/3 amplitude, total energy to KE ratio is x/8. x is:",
        "options": [
            "9",
            "6",
            "2",
            "7"
        ],
        "correctOption": "9",
        "id": 18
    },
    {
        "question": "A body in SHM with 10 cm amplitude is tripled in velocity at 5 cm displacement. New amplitude\u00b2 is:",
        "options": [
            "100",
            "400",
            "700",
            "500"
        ],
        "correctOption": "700",
        "id": 19
    },
    {
        "question": "In SHM, if displacement is half amplitude, ratio of PE to KE is:",
        "options": [
            "1:1",
            "1:4",
            "2:1",
            "1:3"
        ],
        "correctOption": "1:3",
        "id": 20
    },
    {
        "question": "A car accelerates uniformly from rest and covers a distance of 100 m in 5 s. Its acceleration is:",
        "options": [
            "8 m/s\u00b2",
            "10 m/s\u00b2",
            "5 m/s\u00b2",
            "6 m/s\u00b2"
        ],
        "correctOption": "8 m/s\u00b2",
        "id": 21
    },
    {
        "question": "A vector of magnitude 10 units makes an angle of 60\u00b0 with the x-axis. Its y-component is:",
        "options": [
            "10\u221a3/2",
            "10/2",
            "5\u221a3",
            "5"
        ],
        "correctOption": "10\u221a3/2",
        "id": 22
    },
    {
        "question": "The dimensional formula for pressure is:",
        "options": [
            "ML\u207b\u00b9T\u207b\u00b2",
            "MLT\u207b\u00b2",
            "ML\u00b2T\u207b\u00b2",
            "M\u207b\u00b9L\u207b\u00b9T\u207b\u00b2"
        ],
        "correctOption": "ML\u207b\u00b9T\u207b\u00b2",
        "id": 23
    },
    {
        "question": "The moment of inertia of a solid sphere about its diameter is:",
        "options": [
            "2/5 MR\u00b2",
            "3/5 MR\u00b2",
            "1/2 MR\u00b2",
            "2/3 MR\u00b2"
        ],
        "correctOption": "2/5 MR\u00b2",
        "id": 24
    },
    {
        "question": "Which law states that the net external torque on a system is equal to the rate of change of angular momentum?",
        "options": [
            "Newton's First Law",
            "Conservation of Angular Momentum",
            "Newton\u2019s Second Law for Rotation",
            "Kepler's Second Law"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Newton\u2019s Second Law for Rotation",
        "id": 25
    },
    {
        "question": "A parallel plate capacitor having capacitance 12 pF is charged by a battery to 10 V. A porcelain slab of dielectric constant 6.5 is inserted. The work done by the capacitor on the slab is:",
        "options": [
            "508 pJ",
            "692 pJ",
            "560 pJ",
            "600 pJ"
        ],
        "correctOption": "508 pJ",
        "id": 26
    },
    {
        "question": "A solid conducting sphere with charge Q is surrounded by an uncharged conducting hollow shell. If shell is given charge \u20134Q, the new potential difference is:",
        "options": [
            "4 V",
            "V",
            "2 V",
            "\u20132 V"
        ],
        "correctOption": "V",
        "id": 27
    },
    {
        "question": "Two equal resistances in series consume 60 W. When in parallel, the power consumed is:",
        "options": [
            "240 W",
            "120 W",
            "60 W",
            "30 W"
        ],
        "correctOption": "240 W",
        "id": 28
    },
    {
        "question": "An ideal battery of 4 V and resistance R in a potentiometer gives 5 mV across 10 cm of wire. Then R is:",
        "options": [
            "490",
            "495",
            "395",
            "480"
        ],
        "correctOption": "395",
        "id": 29
    },
    {
        "question": "A capacitor of 9 pF is filled with two dielectrics (k1 = 3, k2 = 6). The new capacitance is:",
        "options": [
            "20.25 pF",
            "1.8 pF",
            "45 pF",
            "40.5 pF"
        ],
        "correctOption": "40.5 pF",
        "id": 30
    },
    {
        "question": "The speed of light in the medium is:",
        "options": [
            "minimum on the axis of the beam",
            "maximum on the axis of the beam",
            "the same everywhere in the beam",
            "directly proportional to the intensity I"
        ],
        "correctOption": "minimum on the axis of the beam",
        "id": 31
    },
    {
        "question": "As the beam enters the medium, it will:",
        "options": [
            "travel as a cylindrical beam",
            "converge",
            "diverge",
            "diverge near axis and converge at periphery"
        ],
        "correctOption": "converge",
        "id": 32
    },
    {
        "question": "Eye is modeled as a refracting surface. Distance from surface for focus is:",
        "options": [
            "3.1 cm",
            "4.0 cm",
            "1 cm",
            "2 cm"
        ],
        "correctOption": "3.1 cm",
        "id": 33
    },
    {
        "question": "In Young\u2019s experiment, path difference is (\u215b)\u03bb. Intensity ratio to central fringe is:",
        "options": [
            "0.80",
            "0.94",
            "0.85",
            "0.74"
        ],
        "correctOption": "0.85",
        "id": 34
    },
    {
        "question": "Green light (5303 \u00c5) in double slit gives how many bright fringes between minima:",
        "options": [
            "10",
            "04",
            "09",
            "05"
        ],
        "correctOption": "05",
        "id": 35
    },
    {
        "question": "Heavy nucleus breaks into two. If velocity ratio is 8:27, radius ratio is:",
        "options": [
            "3:2",
            "2:3",
            "4:9",
            "8:27"
        ],
        "correctOption": "3:2",
        "id": 36
    },
    {
        "question": "In hydrogen atom transition to ground state:",
        "options": [
            "kinetic energy decreases, potential energy increases but total remains same",
            "kinetic energy increases, potential and total decrease",
            "kinetic and total decrease, potential increases",
            "kinetic, potential and total energy decrease"
        ],
        "correctOption": "kinetic energy increases, potential and total decrease",
        "id": 37
    },
    {
        "question": "Photoelectric threshold wavelength is 380 nm. With 260 nm, KE is:",
        "options": [
            "1.5 eV",
            "15.1 eV",
            "4.5 eV",
            "3.0 eV"
        ],
        "correctOption": "1.5 eV",
        "id": 38
    },
    {
        "question": "Work function is 4.0 eV. Longest wavelength to emit photoelectrons is:",
        "options": [
            "540 nm",
            "400 nm",
            "310 nm",
            "220 nm"
        ],
        "correctOption": "310 nm",
        "id": 39
    },
    {
        "question": "Radioactive source gives 1600 cps at t=0, 100 cps at t=8s. At t=6s it gives:",
        "options": [
            "250",
            "360",
            "150",
            "200"
        ],
        "correctOption": "200",
        "id": 40
    },
    {
        "question": "Needles of ferro-, para- and diamagnetic materials react to magnet by:",
        "options": [
            "attract N1 strongly, N2 weakly and repel N3 weakly",
            "attract all three",
            "attract N1 and N2 strongly but repel N3",
            "attract N1 strongly, but repel N2 and N3 weakly"
        ],
        "correctOption": "attract N1 strongly, N2 weakly and repel N3 weakly",
        "id": 41
    },
    {
        "question": "Current in coil changes from 5A to 2A in 0.1 s, 50 V induced. Self-inductance is:",
        "options": [
            "0.67 H",
            "1.67 H",
            "3 H",
            "6 H"
        ],
        "correctOption": "1.67 H",
        "id": 42
    },
    {
        "question": "Red LED emits 0.1W uniformly. Electric field amplitude at 1 m is:",
        "options": [
            "2.45 V/m",
            "7.75 V/m",
            "1.73 V/m",
            "5.48 V/m"
        ],
        "correctOption": "2.45 V/m",
        "id": 43
    },
    {
        "question": "AC cannot be measured by DC ammeter because:",
        "options": [
            "A.C cannot pass",
            "A.C changes direction",
            "Avg value is zero",
            "D.C. ammeter gets damaged"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Avg value is zero",
        "id": 44
    },
    {
        "question": "Phase difference between alternating current and emf is \u03c0/2. Not in circuit?",
        "options": [
            "LC",
            "L alone",
            "C alone",
            "R, L"
        ],
        "correctOption": "R, L",
        "id": 45
    },
    {
        "question": "A long straight wire carries a current of 10 A. The magnetic field at a distance of 2 cm from the wire is:",
        "options": [
            "1 \u00d7 10\u207b\u2075 T",
            "10\u207b\u2076 T",
            "1 \u00d7 10\u207b\u2074 T",
            "10\u207b\u2077 T"
        ],
        "correctOption": "1 \u00d7 10\u207b\u2074 T",
        "id": 46
    },
    {
        "question": "A charged particle enters a magnetic field perpendicular to its velocity. The path of the particle is:",
        "options": [
            "Circular",
            "Linear",
            "Parabolic",
            "Elliptical"
        ],
        "correctOption": "Circular",
        "id": 47
    },
    {
        "question": "In an LCR series circuit, the resonance frequency is given by:",
        "options": [
            "1/(2\u03c0\u221a(LC))",
            "1/(2\u03c0RC)",
            "1/(2\u03c0LR)",
            "1/(LC)"
        ],
        "correctOption": "1/(2\u03c0\u221a(LC))",
        "id": 48
    },
    {
        "question": "A radioactive substance has a half-life of 10 days. In how many days will only 1/8th of the substance remain?",
        "options": [
            "30",
            "20",
            "40",
            "10"
        ],
        "correctOption": "30",
        "id": 49
    },
    {
        "question": "The energy of a photon is 3.3 \u00d7 10\u207b\u00b9\u2079 J. Its frequency is (Planck's constant h = 6.626 \u00d7 10\u207b\u00b3\u2074 Js):",
        "options": [
            "5 \u00d7 10\u00b9\u2074 Hz",
            "3 \u00d7 10\u2078 Hz",
            "2 \u00d7 10\u00b9\u2074 Hz",
            "1 \u00d7 10\u2079 Hz"
        ],
        "correctOption": "5 \u00d7 10\u00b9\u2074 Hz",
        "id": 50
    }
]